CHAITANYA GAIKWAD

EDUCATION

Computer Engineering (Graduation) PCCOER Pune University 2019

Computer Engineering (Diploma) Y.B. Patil Polytechnic MSBTE University 2016

SKILLS

Python

Django, Flask, FastAPI, Langchain, React-js

Gen-AI

RAG(Retrieval Augmented Generation)

HTML, CSS, Javascript

REST APIs

OOP

VectorDB: Pinecone

Sql: PostgreSQL

NoSql: MongoDB

AWS: Lambda, S3

Docker

Postman

Github, Bitbucket

PROFILE

I having been working with **Python** since 4 years now. I have explored fields like **Web Development**, and **Gen-AI**. I have worked with different frameworks like **Django**, **Flask**, **Langchain**, **FastAPI** and **React-Js**. I have proficiency in building **REST APIs**. Additionally, I am well-versed in tools like GitHub, Docker, Bitbucket and JIRA.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Particle41 India LTD

Nov 2022 - Present

About company

The company works with Enterprise Solutions, Retail & eCommerce, Startups, Solo-Founders, SaaS Platforms, Cloud Providers etc providing solutions related to web development, Back-End Systems, CMS Platforms, SaaS Applications, Front-End Coding, AI / Machine Learning, UX/UI and much more.

My roles

- 1. Create chat bots using Generative AI, RAG and Langchain.
- 2. Indexing (RAPTOR indexing technique).
- 3. Hit slack APIs to extract conversations.
- 4. Image processing to extract texts from image.
- 5. Web scrapping to extract textual data from web pages.
- 6. Data cleaning before ingestion.
- 7. Data embedding (vectorization).
- 8. Store embeddings on AWS S3.
- 9. Indexing on vector DB (Pinecone)
- 10. Writing prompts.
- 11. Used LLMs: Openai.
- 12. Use FastAPI to create a micro-service and expose APIs according to the requirements and deploy it using docker.

LANGUAGES

CONTACT

7447-651-902

chaitanyagaikwad2023@gmail.com

Purna Nagar, Chinchwad, Pune, 411019

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Neemtree Tech Labs

Jan 2021 - Aug 2022

About company

The company is into Cloud App Development, Mobile App Development, Digital Marketing and Web development.

My roles

- 1. Backend: Developing websites using Django and Flask.
- 2. Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript and frameworks like Bootstrap and Tailwind.
- 3. Deployment: Deploying website on Heroku or Digital Ocean like hosting platforms.
- 4. Research: To make sure or find which hosting platform or database is suitable for particular application.
- 5. Databases used: Mongodb Atlas, PostgreSQL.

Python Developer

Cravita Technologies

Jun 2019 - Jun 2020

About company

The company was into web development, logo design and creating mobile apps.

My roles

- 1. Backend: Developing websites using Django and Flask.
- 2. Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript and frameworks like Bootstrap.